PERSONAL

- Name
 Kangogo Joel
- ↑ Address 07 30405 Tenges
- Phone number +254722146545
- **†∔ Gender** Male
- Nationality
 Kenyan
- Website
 https://jkangogo.github.io
- LinkedIn

 https://www.linkedin.com/in/kango
 joel-a43655199

KANGOGO JOEL

I am an innovative software engineer driven to solve complex challenges. I can merge deep technical proficiency with strategic leadership, allowing me to grow through continuous learning and improvement. With experience in mobile, web, RFID/NFC/IoT programming, technical writing, R&D, and tech mentorship, I am driven to deliver solutions that push the boundaries of innovation.



WORK EXPERIENCE

Jan 2022 - Present Software Engineer

J-Class Solutions Inc,, Danbury CT

Developed and programmed RFID/NFC/BLE IoT devices for innovative home automation solutions and implemented AI algorithms for an LLM

Autocomplete application.

Jan 2021 - Present Vetted Software Engineer

LD Talent, California

Worked on mobile and web applications, focusing on coding and wireframe design.

Reviewed technical blogs.

Aug 2023 - Apr 2024 Research Admin

GIZ, Kenya, Nairobi

Delivered a comprehensive R&D report on software services, aiding strategic insights for GIZ Kenya.

Nov 2020 - Apr 2021 Software Engineer Intern

3moderm Systems Ltd., Nairobi

As a software Engineer Intern I contributed to the mobile version of a rental management system, enhancing property management efficiency.



EDUCATION AND QUALIFICATIONS

Sep 2016 - Mar 2022 Bachelor of Science in Information Technology

Kibabii University, Bungoma

Full-time student taking BSC. Information Technology

Jan 2012 - Nov 2015 High School KCSE

Kabarnet High School, Kabarnet

KCSE Certificate



SKILLS

Mobile app development
(Java, Kotlin, Flutter)

Web development (HTML,
JavaScript, PHP, WP, Joomla

Database (MySQL, PostgreSQL,
MongoDB)

NFC/RFID/BLE Programming
(Java-pi4J, Python)

Data Science & Machine
Learning (Python, R)

★★★★★



TASKS & ACHIEVEMENTS

J-class Solutions Inc,

Senior level | Software Engineer Danbury, United States 2022-01-01 | Currently working here

Programming of RFID/NFC IOT Devices for Home Automation

I have collaborated with J-Class Solutions' team of skilled engineers to develop innovative programs
that utilize RFIDs/NFCs, IoT, and LLM technologies for home automation and text prediction AI. Through
our joint efforts, we have created cutting-edge solutions allowing seamless, secure, and convenient
control of various home automation systems, enhancing homeowners' overall quality of life.

LD Talent

Mid-level | Software Engineer California, United States 2021-01-01 | 2024-12-01

Vetted freelance software engineer specializing in mobile/web application development.

A day in my life entails writing code for mobile applications, designing wireframes for mobile and web
UI, and creating web content. As a skilled freelance software engineer specializing in mobile and web
application development, I focus on delivering high-quality solutions that meet client needs. My daily
routine includes crafting efficient code for mobile applications, designing intuitive wireframes for both
mobile and web user interfaces, and producing engaging web content that captivates users.

GIZ Kenya

Senior level | R&D Admin Nairobi, Kenya 2023-08-01 | 2024-04-01

Assumed the Role of R&D Assistant and delivered a comprehensive report for Software and Software Services

In collaboration with GIZ Kenya, Kenya's Ministry of ICT & Digital Economy (MoICDE) project aimed to
reform ICT, especially the software industry. The rationale was to assess the sector's efficacy, suitability,
and structure in fostering agility, innovation, and value creation. The project successfully presented a
reform report to GIZ and MoICDE containing all the findings, recommendations, and implementation
plans.

Prime Dimensions Ltd.

Senior level | Web Developer Nairobi, Kenya 2023-11-01 | 2024-01-01

Developed a business website for Prime Dimensions Limited

I developed a Joomla website for Prime Dimensions Limited with custom HTML, CSS, and PHP. This
included responsive design, SEO, project showcase, detailed pages for services, easy CMS, multilingual
support, and contact forms. I also did all the content writing needed to highlight their engineering
expertise. https://primedimensions.co.ke/

3modern systems Ltd.

Internship & Graduate | Software Engineer Intern Nairobi, Kenya 2020-11-01 | 2021-04-01

Participated in the development of the mobile version of a rental management System for 3Modern Systems

 A management tool that keeps records of all your properties, tenants, payments, monetary usages, and generation of expenditure reports. With this management system, we provide an amazing solution to property owners to minimize their rental losses.

https://github.com/jkangogo/3Modern-PropertyManager https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.threemodern.threepmanager



Fundamentals of Cybersecurity: Certificate | 2021

Data Science: Certificate | 2021 **Machine Learning:** Certificate | 2021 **Wordpress:** Certificate | 2020

IT Industrial Training: Certificate | 2019



REFERENCES

The University of Pro

Prof. Christopher Chepken

Nairobi

+254 722977672 chepken@gmail.com

MICDE Sectoral Working Group

George Wanyama +254 799751405

GeorgeWOkado@gmail.com

J-Class Solutions Inc, Thomas Garben

+1 914 874 7318 tom@j-class.com